Humanity takes center stage at TED,
يتركز محور الحديث في TED على البشرية،
but I would like to add a voice for the animals,
ولكني أود أن أضيف صوتًا للحيوانات،
whose bodies and minds and spirits shaped us.
التي شكلتنا أجسامها وعقولها وأرواحها.
Some years ago, it was my good fortune
قبل بضعة سنوات، كان من جميل حظي
to meet a tribal elder on an island
أن أقابل شيخ قبيلة على جزيرة
not far from Vancouver.
ليست ببعيدة عن مدينة فانكوفر.
His name is Jimmy Smith,
كان اسمه جيمي سميث،
and he shared a story with me
وقد شاركني قصة
that is told among his people,
يرويها أبناء قبيلته،
who call themselves the Kwikwasut'inuxw.
والذين يطلقون على أنفسهم اسم كويكواسوتينوك.
Once upon a time, he told me,
قال لي، في قديم الزمان
all animals on Earth were one.
كانت جميع حيوانات الأرض حيوانًا واحدًا.
Even though they look different on the outside,
وبالرغم من كونها تبدو في ظاهرها مختلفة،
inside, they're all the same,
في الداخل، هي جميعها متشابهة،
and from time to time they would gather
وكانت تجتمع من الحين إلى الآخر
at a sacred cave deep inside the forest
في كهف مقدس في عمق الغابة
to celebrate their unity.
للاحتفال بتوحدها.
When they arrived,
وعندما تصل الحيوانات،
they would all take off their skins.
تخلع جلودها.
Raven shed his feathers, bear his fur,
يلقي الغراب ريشه، ويلقي الدب فروته،
and salmon her scales,
وتلقي أسماك السلمون قشورها،
and then, they would dance.
ومن ثم، تبدأ جميعًا بالرقص.
But one day, a human made it to the cave
ولكن في أحد الأيام، وصل بشري إلى الكهف
and laughed at what he saw
وضحك على ما رآه
because he did not understand.
لأنه لم يفهم.
Embarrassed, the animals fled,
هربت الحيوانات محرجة،
and that was the last time
وكانت تلك المرة الأخيرة
they revealed themselves this way.
التي كشفوا بها أنفسهم بهذه الطريقة.
The ancient understanding that underneath
إن الفهم القديم الذي قلل من قدر
their separate identities, all animals are one,
هوياتهم المنفصلة، كل الحيوانات واحد،
has been a powerful inspiration to me.
قد كان إلهامًا قويًا بالنسبة لي.
I like to get past the fur, the feathers
أود تناسي الفروة والريش
and the scales.
والقشور.
I want to get under the skin.
أود أن أصل إلى ما تحت الجلد.
No matter whether I'm facing a giant elephant
سواء كنت أواجه فيلًا ضخمًا
or a tiny tree frog,
أو ضفدع أشجار صغير،
my goal is to connect us with them, eye to eye.
فإن هدفي هو ربطنا بهم، العين بالعين.
You may wonder, do I ever photograph people?
ربما تستغربون، هل سبق وأن صورت أشخاصًا؟
Sure. People are always present in my photos,
بالتأكيد، الناس حاضرون دومًا في صوري،
no matter whether they appear
سواء أظهروا
to portray tortoises
لتمثيل سلحفاة
or cougars
أو كوجر (أسود أمريكية)
or lions.
أو أسود.
You just have to learn how to look past their disguise.
عليك فقط أن تعلم كيف تتناسى تنكرهم.
As a photographer,
وكمصور،
I try to reach beyond the differences
أحاول أن ألج إلى ما وراء الاختلافات
in our genetic makeup
في تركيبنا المورثي
to appreciate all we have in common
لتقدير كل ما نملكه من أشياء مشتركة
with every other living thing.
مع كل كائن حي آخر.
When I use my camera,
عندما أستخدم كاميرتي،
I drop my skin
ألقي بجلدي
like the animals at that cave
كما فعلت الحيوانات بذلك الكهف
so I can show who they really are.
حتى أستطيع أن أظهر الحقيقة التي هم عليها.
As animals blessed
وكما أن الحيوانات مباركة
with the power of rational thought,
بقوة التفكير العقلاني،
we can marvel at the intricacies of life.
بإمكاننا أن نستغرب من تعقيدات الحياة.
As citizens of a planet in trouble,
وكسكان لكوكب في مشكلة،
it is our moral responsibility
إنه من مسئوليتنا الأخلاقية
to deal with the dramatic loss in diversity of life.
أن نتعامل مع الخسارة المفاجئة في تنوع الحياة.
But as humans with hearts,
وكبشر يمتلكون قلوبًا،
we can all rejoice in the unity of life,
نستطيع جميعًا أن نبتهج في وحدة الحياة،
and perhaps we can change
وربما يمكننا أن نغير
what once happened in that sacred cave.
ما حدث مرة في ذلك الكهف المقدس.
Let's find a way to join the dance.
لنجد طريقة للانضمام إلى الرقص.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)